You can't run from your past.
Creed III is a drama, action film directed by Michael B. Jordan.
After dominating the boxing world, Adonis Creed has
thrived in his career and family life.
When a childhood friend and former boxing prodigy, Damian Anderson, resurfaces after serving a
long sentence in prison, he is eager to prove that he deserves his shot in the ring.
The face-off between former friends is more than just a fight.
To settle the score, Adonis must put his future on the line to
battle Damian — a fighter with nothing to lose.
Adonis Creed, played by Michael B. Jordan.
Bianca Creed, played by Tessa Thompson.
Damian 'Dame' Anderson, played by Jonathan Majors.
Mary-Anne Creed, played by Phylicia Rashād.
Amara Creed, played by Mila Davis-Kent.
Tony 'Little Duke' Evers, played by Wood Harris.
Creed III is a 2023 American sports drama film
starring and directed by Michael B.
Jordan in his directorial debut, and produced by Jordan, Irwin Winkler, Charles Winkler, William Chartoff,
David Winkler, Ryan Coogler, Elizabeth Raposo, Jonathan Glickman and Sylvester Stallone.
It is the sequel to Creed II (2018), the third installment in the Creed
film series, and the ninth overall in the Rocky franchise.
The film was written by Keenan Coogler and Zach Baylin from
a story they co-wrote with Ryan Coogler.
The film sees the accomplished and recently retired boxer Adonis Creed (portrayed by Jordan) come
face-to-face with his childhood friend and former boxing prodigy Damian Anderson (Jonathan Majors).
Tessa Thompson, Wood Harris, Mila Davis-Kent, Florian
Munteanu, and Phylicia Rashad also star.
A third Creed film was officially announced in September 2019, alongside Jordan's return;
he was also confirmed to be making his directorial debut in October 2020.
Majors and the remainder of the cast joined between November 2021 and September 2022; Creed III is the first film in the
series not to feature Sylvester Stallone reprising his role as Rocky Balboa, though he remained as a producer.
Principal photography began in January 2022 and lasted until that April, with
filming locations including Los Angeles, Tampa, and Georgia.
Creed III premiered in Mexico City on February 9, 2023, which coincided with Jordan's 36th birthday, and was released in the United States on March 3 as
the first film distributed by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures after its acquisition by Amazon and the dissolution of United Artists Releasing.
The film received positive reviews from critics for Jordan's
direction, the story, performances, and fighting sequences.
Like its predecessors, the film was a box office success, grossing over $276 million worldwide,
making it the highest-grossing Creed film and the second highest-grossing Rocky film.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
philadelphia, pennsylvania, sports, deaf, sequel.
The tone is emotional and intense.